A Guide to the Alice and Phoebe Cary Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #6978
Alice and Phoebe Cary Collection 1850-1869
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
6978
ca. 24 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 10 Jan 1963
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - "Hunter's Song" by Alice Cary, n.d.; AMsS, 1 p.
- Letters
  - Susan Cary to "My dear sister", 1850 Jun 30; ALS, 4 p.
    [Describes trip from Cincinnati to Wareham, Massachusetts; her travels by steamer and rail, visits to Canada by the wire bridge and the state prison in Auburn, New York; visit to Niagra Falls and Buffalo; and her steamer trip down the Hudson River to New York City. ]
  - Alice Cary to "My dear sister", 1850 Aug 12; ALS, 3 p.
    [Mentions a visit to John Greenleaf Whitter's house near Boston and his return visit to the Cary house.]
  - Phoebe Cary to Rev. H. W. Parker, 1852 Jan 6; ALS, 2 p.
    [Sends the conclusion of a story and mentions Alice Cary's ill health.]
  - Alice Cary to "My dear sister", 1862 Dec 13; ALS, 8 p.
    [Writes about the death of a sister (Elmina ?).]
  - Phoebe Cary to Lucy [Carnahan], 1868 Aug; ALS, 4 p.
    [Mentions Dr. Charles F. Deems and Horace Greeley. ]
  - [ Alice Cary] to Lucy [Carnahan], 1869 Sep or Oct; AL, 3 p.
    [Incomplete letter, mentions efforts to have Lucy's story published in
    Harpers
    . ]
  - Phoebe Cary to Lucy [Carnahan], n.y. Jan 28; ALS, 3 p.
    [Describes her trip to Washington to attend a reception.]
  - Alice Cary to Lucy [Carnahan], n.y. Apr 14; AL, 5 p.
    [Concerns negotiations with the
    Weekly Home Journal
    to get one of Lucy's stories published, also attempts to publish some of her own works.]
  - Phoebe Cary to Lucy [Carnahan], n.y. Apr 26; ALS, 5 p.
    [Concerning argument with Whitelaw Reid about the "perfectly contemptible tone of the
    Tribune
    toward women's rights."]
  - Alice Cary to Lucy [Carnahan], n.y. May 18; ALS, 3 p.
    [Mentions Sunday night social gathering at the Cary home, also mentions Alice Cary's recent illness.]
  - [ Phoebe Cary] to "My dear child", n.y. May 21; AL, 4 p.
    [Mentions Sunday night's guests; her note of apology to Whitelaw Reid concerning a dispute over women's rights; and sending a story to
    Galaxy
    and to
    for review.]
  - [ Phoebe Cary] to Lucy [Carnahan], n.y. Jun 16; AL, 4 p.
    [Discusses plans for a wedding and other social events.]
  - Phoebe Cary to "My dear sister", n.y. Jul 8; ALS, 3 p.
    [Mentions Elmina's failing health, possible travel plans, and a repeated marriage proposal.]
  - Alice Cary to Lucy [Carnahan], n.y. Aug 5; ALS, 4 p.
    [Sent Lucy's stories to
    Repository
    and
    for review.] fragmentary
  - Phoebe Cary to Lucy [Carnahan], n.y. [Oct 13]; ALS, 3 p.
    [Mentions plans for a trip to the country.]
  - Phoebe Cary to Lucy [Carnahan], n.d.; ALS, 4 p.
    [Discusses the renovation of a house and the ill health of Lucy's mother.]
  - Phoebe Cary to Lucy [Carnahan], n.d.; ALS, 2 p.
    [Writes to assure Lucy that an article in the
    Home Journal
    was not intended as a criticism of her work.]
  - Alice Cary to Lucy [Carnahan], n.d.; ALS, 3 p.
    [Discusses poor pay for being published and plans to take in lodgers in the fall; also mentions attempts to have stories published in various magazines.]
  - Alice Cary to Lucy [Carnahan], n.d.; ALS, 4 p.
    [Mentions an article concerning Lucy in the
    , her own health and the condition of Lucy's mother, and plans to visit James Cooper. ]
  - Alice Cary to Lucy [Carnahan], n.d.; ALS, 4 p.
    [Discusses publication of "Elizabeth's Heifer" in the November edition of
    Harper's
    and the possible publication of Lucy's story in
    Demorest's
  - Alice Cary to unknown, n.d.; ALS, 2 p.
    [Concerning a death in the family.] fragmentary
  - Alice Cary to unknown, n.d.; ALS, 5 p.
    [Concerning a promise made to Susan B. Anthony to write for the
    Revolution
  - [ Phoebe Cary] to Lucy [Carnahan], n.d.; AL, 5 p.
    [Discusses her attendance of poetry readings and social functions.] fragmentary